Guide to the Stanford University, Department of History, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
- General Correspondence, 1903-1961
  - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    (spring): C.F. Brand, combined majors, proposed library survey, H. Quint, P. Rhinelander, undesirability of D students as history majors.
    (summer): Death of H.E. Cutler, A. DeConde, D. Fahrenbache E.A. Schaper correspondence, E.W. Lyon, report for accreditation committee of Western College Association, P. Rhinelander.
  - 1959 (autumn) (Box 3, Folder 89)
    Bailey Book Fund, C.A. Buss, NATO professorship, transfer of credits from Vienna, PCB program for Sept. (1960), K. Von Klemperer, P. Rhinelander (directorship of Hoover Institute, promotion of T. C. Smith, W.L. Langer), F.E. Terman (need for more history staff, report on A.B. in history).
  - 1960 (winter) (Box 3, Folder 90)
    A New History of the Paris Peace Conference (letter to W.G. Campbell), considerable correspondence of J.J. Johnson concerning his research is scattered throughout this folder, George F. Kennan, course for overseas campuses, J.T.C. Liu, T.W. Lyman, comments on midterms (Bailey to McCord), J.G. Oswald, fellowship funds (Wright to Otis), The Ugly American (Buss to Pomeroy), P. Rhinelander (appointment of Spitz and Liu), H. Ross, L. Spitz, C.W. Gaylord Foundation Grant, F.E. Terman (Pease, Coe Grant), University of the Seven Seas.
    (NOTE: In folders 91-94 often the correspondence of several of the Department's senior men [especially Johnson and Buss, with regard to their travels and research] is scattered, being filed under the name of the corresponding party rather than that of the Department member).
  - 1960 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    (spring): Field project in Yugoslavia (Vucinich to Burkhardt), A. DeConde, T. Hammond (bibliography on books about Soviet foreign relations), Hilgard (Committee on Hoover Institute), J.J. Johnson's opinions on several (political) issues (Johnson to Hornig), J. Kuehl, J.T.C. Liu, H. Lutz (papers of Sudeten Germans), David Potter, P. Rhinelander (chair in Armenian Studies, Russian exchange), justification of History Department expansion (Wright to Ryan), J.L. Snell (Committee on Graduate Study in History), J.E.W. Sterling (Coe Professorship), F.E. Terman (hiring of Potter), M.S. Young (Armenian Studies).
    (summer): Comments on high school history (Bailey to Braden), David Potter, P. Rhinelander (appointment of Potter).
  - 1960 (autumn) (Box 3, Folder 92)
    Gordon Craig, Scottish History Collection (Lyman to Gorham), G.F. Kennan, George Knoles, Rollie E. Poppino, David Potter, James Ragland, P. Rhinelande (recommendations of Gordon Craig).
  - 1961 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    (winter): A. Bowker (scholarships, elimination of M.A. thesis), H. Maki (member of Japanese Diet; exchange of letters with C.A. Buss), R. Poppino. Also, much assorted J.J. Johnson correspondence.
    (spring): John M. Allison & C.A. Buss, American Friends Service Committee, Proposed Coe American History Studies program, Robert Blum to C.A. Buss (Asia Foundation, Department of State), Library microfilm acquisitions (Bailey to Brooks), Wallace E. Davies, A. DeConde, Gene Dulin (concern over right-wingers) History Department European offerings (Wright to E.M. Grieder), J. Ragland, P. Rhinelander (Department business), Wright to Terman (improving large classes).
  - 1961 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    (summer): Overseas study of Ph.D. candidates (Wright to Brooks), C.A. Buss (materials obtained in the Orient), A. DeConde, History Department's application for inclusion in the National Defense Act Fellowship Program, possible endowed chair in History of Science and Technology (Wright to Dornbusch), History Department honors, A. Nevins, W. Vucinich (report on research), P. Rhinelander (need for more Western Civ. instructors), Library microfilm acquisitions.
    (autumn): J.H. Meyer Fund (Barclay to White), G.C. Boyce, C.A. Buss, W. Davies, J. Raglund (first to read Cordell Hull Papers), Department fellowships (Wright to Suppes), D. Thompson, J.F. Tierney (Ford Foundation), letter to H.S. Truman, undergraduate education (Pease to Wert), European Studies at Stanford.
- Correspondence pertaining to the placement of academic personnel, 1906-1947
  - Correspondents A-H (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - A H.B. Adams (re R.D. Hunt)., Pre-1906:
    - A E.D. Adams, George B. Adams (re S.L. Mims and Robert K. Richardson), Charles Andrews (re S.L. Ware), Charles Ambler, Herman V. Ames (re Eugene C. Barker)., 1906-16:
    - A Thomas P. Abernathy., Post 1916:
    - B S.G.W. Benjamin, Mary T. Blauvelt, J. Bowman, Edward Bonner., Pre-1906:
    - B Walter G. Beach, H.E. Bolton, Beverly Bond, Gilbert G. Benjamin, request for recommendations about E.C. Barker., 1906-16:
    - B George Burr (re C.C. Eckhardt), George H. Blakeslee (re L.H. Jenks), Samuel F. Bemis., Post 1916:
    - C I.J. Cox, E.M. Clish (re R.D. Hunt), Heber D. Curtis (re R.D. Hunt), Archibald Coolidge (re W. Lichtenstein)., Pre-1906:
    - C R.C. Clark, Carl Christophelsmeir, Frank W. Chandler (re E.C. Griffith)., 1906-1916:
    - D G. Deutsch., Pre-1906:
    - D John C. Dunning (including recommendations of him), M.E. Dailey (re S.B. Harding), Alfred L.P. Dennis (re W.E. Lunt and others)., 1906-16:
    - D William A. Dunning (re L.H. Jenks), Charles W. Dabney (re E.C. Griffith)., Post 1916:
    - E C.C. Eckhardt., 1920:
    - F John A. Fairlie., Pre-1906:
    - F J.W. Fertig, F.G. Franklin, R.B. Fulton (re B. Bond)., 1906-16:
    - G E.F. Gay (re W. Lichtenstein), F.A. Golder., 1906-16:
    - G Elmer C. Griffith., 1920:
    - H R.D. Hunt, Charles Haskins, E.D. Henderson., Pre-1906:
    - H A.B. Hart (re W.E. Dodd and F.E. Riley D.F. Houstin (?) (re E.C. Barker), A.E. Harvey, Charles Haskins (re E.C. Barker and C.E. Fryer), E. M. Hulme., 1906-16:
    - H H.S. Hadley (re C.C. Eckhardt), Carl ton Mayer (re L.H. Jenks), Charles Haskins (re C.W. David, R.A. Newhall and C.F. Brand), C.R. Hicks., Post 1916:
  - Correspondents J-Z (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - J D.S. Jordan (re E.L. Hood)., Pre-1906:
    - J D.S. Jordan (re Dr. Fryer, S.B. Harding), J.F. Jameson., 1906-16:
    - J Leland H. Jenks, Marcus W. Jernegan (re A.E. Harvey)., Post 1916:
    - K L.K. Koontz, Frank J. Klingberg, A. C. Krey (re L.H. Jenks)., Post 1916:
    - L Walter Lichtenstein., 1907:
    - M C.H. McIlwain., Pre-1906:
    - M A.C. McLaughlin (re several men), William MacDonald (re L.B. Shippee), Raymond McFarland, J.F. Millspaugh (re G.O. Virtue)., 1906-16:
    - M T.M. Marshall (re C.C. Eckhardt), H.P. McClintic (?) (re E.C. Griffith), Phillip Meyers (re E.C. Griffith)., Post 1916:
    - N J.B. Newell., 1902:
    - N Thomas Newlin (re P.A. Martin)., 1908:
    - N Wallace Notestein., 1920:
    - P J.W. Park (with recommendations, including one by Woodrow Wilson), F.W. Putnam (re Mr. Brandelier)., Pre-1906:
    - P F.L. Paxson., 1908:
    - R Recommendations for B. Bond by I. Remsen and F.L. Riley., 1906:
    - R Adolf Rein., 1912:
    - S E.E. Sperry, G.L. Sherger, J.O. Sumner (re E.F. Henderson)., Pre-1906:
    - S Lester B. Shippee, Bernard C. Steiner (re B. Bond)., 1906-16:
    - S H.M. Stephens (re W.C. Barnes), B.E. Schmidt., Post 1916:
    - T F.J. Turner (re R.C. Clark and Willard), Francis N. Thorpe, Everett L. Thorndike., Pre-1906:
    - T F.J. Turner (re Pahlow), J.W. Thompson, Lynn Thorndike., 1906-16:
    - T P.J. Treat., 1919:
    - V J.M. Vincent (re B. Bond and S.L. Ware)., 1908 & 1909:
    - W J.E. Winston., 1908:
    - W H.E. Wildes, James Willard (re C.C. Eckhardt)., 1920-21:
    - Z George F. Zook., 1920:
  - Correspondents A - Z, (names in parentheses are those of person considered for positions in the Department), 1946-47 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    (Willard F. Bliss), Carl Bridenbaugh (re R .E. Smith) Verner W. Crane (re Sam C. McCullough), (Eart Cranston), Ralph Gabriel (suggestions), (John Duffy), Thomas H. Greer, (Paul L. Hanna), (Merrill Jensen), Louis K. Koontz, A.C. Krey, John A. Krout, (William H. Maehl), (Gordon H. McNeil), Franklin C. Palm (re R. Brace), (Stanley M. Page), Fred Paxson, Rockefeller Foundation, Tracy E. Strevey, (Gordon Wright).
    (The following persons were considered for position in the Department; recommendations are included in the folder but not listed here).
    Far Eastern: Hugh Borton, D.N. Rowe, Knight Biggerstaff, C. Martin Wilbur, Richard D. Weigle, Charles C. Stelle, Chester A. Bain.
    Russian: Ronald Thompson, Albert Parry, Sydney S. Harcave, Gustav F. Johnson, M.I. Finley, Robert S. Eccles, Joel G. Colton, James E. King.
- History Club
  - Minutes, 1914-16 (Box 4, Folder 98)
- Minutes and Other Records, 1905-1962
  - History Department Minutes, (for special items incorporated in the minutes see 99A), 1905-15 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Additional Documents, 1905-15 (Box 4, Folder 99A)
    - Suggested courses for 1st year history majors., Aug 1905
    - Suggested courses for 1st year history majors., Aug 1907
    - Letter from Prof. Fairclough requesting library funds for Roman history., Oct 1907
    - Statement of the Requirements of the Department of History in regard to Examination and Thesis for the Master's Degree., Apr 1909
    - Recommended list of serial publications, 1909-10., Dec 1909
    - Clerical assistants for instructors., Sep 1910
    - Library Funds Committee, Sep 1911
    - Book Fund, 1913-14., May 1913:
    - History Club, Departmental Library, vocational aims of the history major., Oct 1913
    - More on Departmental Library., Jan 1914
    - More on Departmental Library., Feb 1914
    - History Department M.A. requirements., Apr 1915
    - History Library rules, report on library sets., Sep 1915
    - Proposals for rules in History Library, Oct 1915
  - History Department Minutes, (for special items incorporated in the minutes see 100A), 1916-22 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Additional Documents, 1916-22 (Box 4, Folder 100A)
    - Requirements of the History Department for M.A. degree., Mar 1916
    - Memo from R.L. Wilbur dealing with department organization., 18 May 1916:
    - Report of Departmental Committee on the 4 quarter system., Nov 1916
    - Requirements for a minor in history, Dec 1917
    - High school teachers' minor in history., Dec 1918
    - Report of the Departmental Committee on the disposal of the Library Fund., Feb 1920
    - Ex-members of the deaprtment., Mar 1921
    - Committee on Lower Division., Mar 1922
    - Summer Quarter Graduate Students., Summer 1922:
    - Degree Requirement Committee report, M.A. Examinations Committee., Oct 1922
  - History Department Minutes, (For special items incorporated in the minutes see 101A), 1923-29 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Additional Documents, 1923-29 (Box 4, Folder 101A)
    - Graduate students., Summer 1923:
    - Enrollment in courses., June 1923:
    - Jewel Fund distribution., Dec 1923
    - School of Social Sciences., Jan 1924
    - Canadian materials for R.G. Trotter., Feb 1924
    - Questions Propounded by Committee on Lower Division., Mar 1925
    - Report on Department Requirements for Ph.D. Degree., Apr 1925
    - Requirements for M.A., Oct 1926
  - History Department Minutes, 1929-34 (Box 4)
  - History Department Minutes, 1934-39 (Box 4)
  - History Department Minutes of Special Meetings to Consider Policy and Program, 7-28 Feb 1938 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    Also includes reports of several committees, as well as minor and supplementary reports:
    1. Committee on M.A. Requirements.
    2. Committee to Consider Revision of Department Ph.D. Requirements.
    3. Proposed Honors Course in History.
    4. Committee on Undergraduate Requirements.
  - History Department Meetings, Agenda and Documents of Topics to be Considered., 1937-38: (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - History Department Meetings, Agenda and Topics for Meetings., 1939-41: (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - History Department Meetings, Agenda and Topics for Meetings., Spring 1941: (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - History Department Meetings, Material for Meetings., Summer 1941: (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - History Department Meetings, Material for Meetings., Summer and Autumn 1942: (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - History Department Meetings, Material for Meetings., 1943: (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - History Department Meetings, Material for Meetings., 1944-45: (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - History Department Meetings, Material for Meetings., Winter 1947: (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - History Department Meetings, Material for Meetings., 1948-49: (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - National University Proposal, (E.J. McDermott, E.D. Adams et. al.)., 1916 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Washington (D.C.) University Center (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Honor System (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Committee on Educational Preparation for Foreign Service, 1915-18 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    G.L. Swiggett, P.P. Claxton, Wilbur Carr (Head of Consular Service), John Clausen.
  - History Text Controversy, 1918-23 (Box 5, Folder 116)
    (Adams was on Calif. History Textbook Committee).
  - California Committee on History Texts, A.C. Olney., 1918-23 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - California Committee on History Texts, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - E.D. Adams: War Issues Course, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - E.D. Adams: AHA Committee of Nine, 1915-16 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - E.D. Adams: California Teachers' Association History Section, 1909-10 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Independent Study, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Independent Study, 1934-35 (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - History of Western Civilization, 1937 and 1941 (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - History of Western Civilization, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - History of Western Civilization, 1935 (?) (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - History of Western Civilization, 1935-38 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    Documents pertaining to the transfer of Citizenship to Western Civ.; Various reports on Western Civ. courses.
  - History of Western Civilization, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - History of Western Civilization, 1944-45 (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - Liberal Arts - History of Western Civilization, 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 130)
  - History of Western Civilization, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Lecture to Prospective History Majors, 1934 (?) (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - History Department Annual Reports to the President:, 1917-18; 1919-20; 1937-38; 1938-39; 1939-40 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - History Department and the President, (Notes of meetings with E.E.R.)., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Elementary History, 1931-32 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Proposed School of Social Sciences, 1934-35 (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Departmental Philosophy and Plans, 1929-44 (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - Department Plans, Staff biographies; recommendations for salary increases., Autumn 1949: (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - Course Contents, Enrollments, Requirements Mainly, 1929 and 1934-35 (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - Content of Courses, Revisions, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - History Department, Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Syllabus Fund, 1905-40
    - Jewel Fund Appropriation, 1908-40
    - Enrollment in Syllabus-Paying Classes, 1930-31-1939-40
    - Teaching Load, 1939-40
  - Miscellaneous, 1937-39 (Box 5, Folder 142)
    Some important papers about the department at this time; evaluations of the department by members
  - Independent Study, Graduate Study, Ordering Library Books (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - Papers Concerning Department Location, (i.e., in Social Science or Humanities or as a separate school)., 1944 (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - General Memoranda, Autumn 1945 (Box 5, Folder 145)
    Includes reports of members' activities.
  - Leaves of Absence, New Courses, Time Schedule for Ph. D. Candidates, 1947: (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Problems of Leaves of Absence, 1948: (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - War Council/Military Pre-Induction Course, 1941-42: (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - Stanford University War Council, 1942: (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - Miscellaneous, 1949: (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Staff Suggestions, 1949: (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Faculty Material for President's Report, 1949-50 (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - New Courses, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Chair, 1948-49 (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Gifts Committee; Expansion in the Department, Summer 1945 (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - History Department Annual Budgets, 1908-09 to 1920-21 (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - History Department Annual Budgets, 1929-30 to 1944-45 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    Includes evaluation of the staff, letters of resignation, recommendations for promotion, etc.
  - History Department Annual Budgets, 1945-46 to 1951-52 (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - History Department Appointments, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 159)
  - History Department Joint Chair in Economics and History, 1957-59 (Box 6, Folder 160)
    Includes candidates Douglas North and Eric C. Lampard.
  - Appointments Some Miscellany, 1929-31; 1931-35 (Box 6, Folder 161)
  - Arthur Bestor appointment in History-Humanities, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 162)
  - P.A. Martin Material (Box 6, Folder 163)
  - Deferments & Criteria; History Courses; Fellowships, 1941-42: (Box 6, Folder 164)
  - Replacement for Arthur Wright, 1959-60 (Box 6, Folder 165)
    List of suggested names, suggestions by Wright. Correspondence among T.A. Bailey, G. Wright, P. Rhinelander, James Liu. Suggestions from John Fairbank and Charles O. Hucker.
  - German Appointment., Autumn 1960: (Box 6, Folder 166)
  - Potter Appointment (Box 6, Folder 167)
  - Headship File, 1956: (Box 6, Folder 168)
  - Freidel Replacement File, 1955-56: (Box 6, Folder 169)
    Barker, Beale, Bemis, Craven, DeConde, Deutch, Ehrmann, Gabriel, Gates, Goldmann, Green, Handlin, Harrington, Hill, Holt, Hutchinson, Johnson, Leopold, Link, Lively, Merk, Morris, Palmer, Rudin, Watson.
  - R.W. Lyman File, 1957-58: (Box 6, Folder 170)
  - G.I. Langmuir File, 1957-58: (Box 6, Folder 171)
  - John Teall File, 1957-58: (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - Medieval English History File, 1957-58: (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - English History Replacement File, 1957-58: (Box 6, Folder 174)
  - Don E. Fehrenbacher - summer appointment, Autumn 1958: (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - O'Malley Replacement, 1959-60: (Box 6, Folder 176)
  - History Department Placement Correspondence (Stanford Ph.D.'s)., 1959-61: (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - Placement Correspondence, 1961-62: (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - Ph.D. Minors' File (Box 6, Folder 179)
    Includes Mark Hatfield.
- Problems of Citizenship, 1920-1935
  - Problems of Citizenship as taught at other institutions: Columbia, Dartmouth, Harvard, Iowa, Minnesota. (Box 6, Folder 180)
  - Special Courses for Freshman (put out in 1922 by American Association of University Professors); Education for Citizenship Bulletin of the National Research Council: Honors Courses in American Colleges and Universities, Orientation Courses, the Construction of Orientation Courses fo College Freshmen., (1923) (Box 6)
  - Citizenship Advisory Committee, 1924-29 (Box 6, Folder 181)
  - Problems of Citizenship, Miscellaneous: (Box 6, Folder 182)
    Course origins; 1924-25 outline; outline for discussion sections; study aids, Personal Reflections on Citizenship (by an instructor), 1934; evaluation by a committee for the School of Social Sciences.
  - Problems of Citizenship: Early (Box 6, Folder 183)
    Working papers (ca. 1925). Plans, problems, approach, method, aims, etc.
  - Problems in Citizenship: Minutes of Staff Conferences, 1923-26 (Box 6, Folder 184)
  - Problems in Citizenship: Minutes of Staff Conferences, 1929-33 (Box 6, Folder 185)
  - Assembly Bill 307: Would require a course in constitutional citizenship (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Instructors, 1931 & 1933 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Report to the President, 1933-34 (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Points of View (Box 7, Folder 189)
    Contains correspondence between E.E. Robinson and R.L. Wilbur on a School of Public Affairs at Stanford. (Possible origin of Citizenship course).
  - Grading System, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Problems of Citizenship Examination, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Lower Division Committee on Citizenship, 1920-24 (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - Plans for Books on Orientation (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - Publicity, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - Revision of the Plan for Citizenship and History, 1932-34 (Box 7, Folder 195)
  - Problems of Citizenship, 1933-35 (Box 7, Folder 196)
    Also includes Danner's speed reading and study research.
  - Problems of Citizenship Correspondence
    - A-F. Includes Luther Evans., 1935-20 (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - K-Q. Includes letters of 1920 exploring idea of citizenship course; letter to Howard Meneely explaining end of course and a new approach., 1935-20 (Box 7, Folder 198)
    - R-Z. Includes Mayo Newhall, Henry R. Luce, J.E.Wallace Sterling application, C.E. Rothwell, C.N. Reynolds, Chester Rowell., 1935-23 (Box 7, Folder 199)
  - Syllabus Books, Autumn 1932 (Box 7, Folder 200)
  - Problems of Citizenship, Syllabus Reorganization, 1931-32 (Box 7, Folder 201)
  - Problems of Citizenship, Syllabus Reorganization, 1933-34, 1934-35 (Box 7, Folder 202)
  - Problems of Citizenship, Transcription of Lectures
    - Autumn 1923 (Box 7, Folder 203)
    - Autumn 1924 (Box 7, Folder 204)
    - Autumn 1926-27 (Box 7, Folder 205)
    - 1926-28 (Box 7, Folder 206)
    - 1928 (Box 7, Folder 207)
    - 1928-29 (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - 1929-30 (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - 1930-31, 1931-32 (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - 1932-33 (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - 1933-35 (Box 7, Folder 212)
- Army Specialized Training Program, 1943-1945
  - History 133 Tests (120a) (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - 1. Memo to Dept. Heads from Classification Officer, 29-Sep-43
    - 2. Typed & holograph letter from [Bob] to Charles, undated
    - 3. Part I examination from Savelle.
    - 4. Part I examination from Bailey.
    - 5. Basic Phase Curriculum BE-1, 1st term.
    - 6. Letter to Messrs. Robinson, Bailey, Bradley Barker, Knoles & White from M.S. [Max Savelle], 6-Oct-43
    - 7. List of subject objectives, Parts I, II & III.
    - 8. Holograph notes.
    - 9. Items from memorandum from War Dept.
    - 10. Letter to Charlie from no sig., undated
    - 11. Memo to Savelle re Proposed Contracts with War Department fro Test Construction and Standardization for ASTP.
  - Item Analysis & Explanation of Program Reports, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - 1. Report on Item Analysis for Terms I & II, 1944
    - 2. Purpose & Content of #133 Program - report.
    - 3. Basic Phase Curriculum B-1 - report.
    - 4. What the Teachers Say of American History in the California Public High Schools - report.
    - 5. Letter to University & College Heads from the Director of AST Division re purposes & procedures of ASTP, 5-Mar-43
  - U.S. History Tests - Reports, etc., Summer 1943 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - 1. History 133 grade sheets from 2 classes.
    - 2. Summary of grade distribution, medians, etc. between Bailey and Parker's classes.
    - 3. Analysis of how questions answered, Parts I, II and III.
    - 4. History 133, Term I examination - Includes a page on purposes of the course & examination., Sep-43
    - 5. History 133, Term II examination -, Sep-43
    - 6. History 133, Term III examination -, Sep-43
    - 7. Time Schedule for Reports.
    - 8. Analysis of the Characteristics of the Test in History 133.
    - 9. History 120a examination questions, 26 Jul, 6 Aug, 23 Aug 1943
    - 10. U.S. History test questions.
    - 11. Holograph page of numbers and grades.
  - U.S. History Tests - Part II (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - 1. 2 rough drafts of part of history examination, Sep-43
    - 2. Examination from History 120a, 10-Sep-43
    - 3. Various test questions for make-up of Part II with holograph corrections, revisions & statements.
  - U.S. History Tests - Part IV (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - 1. Rough drafts of examination - holograph revisions by [Parker & Bailey].
  - Army Reports (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - 1. Director's Reports on Instructional Time in Army Program, 23 Oct 1944-27 Aug 1945
    - 2. Weekly Reports on Instruction in AST Units 3905. Form B & some Form C's. (1 report per month saved)., 19 Jul 1943-14 Aug 1944